Guide to the Albert Lemuel Judd Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Albert Lemuel Judd family papers
1861-1944
MS 827
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
Diaries of Albert Lemuel Judd, Katharine Wells Judd, Ethel Gardiner Judd and notes from the diaries of Albert Dunham Judd, members of a New Britain, Connecticut family involved in manufacturing and active in community affairs. The papers also include five memo books and three miscellaneous documents.
Judd, Albert Lemuel, 1864-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Whitlock's in 1973.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Albert Lemuel Judd Family papers contain the diaries of Albert Lemuel Judd (b. 1864), his sister, Katherine Wells Judd, and his wife, Ethel (Gardiner) Judd (b. 1869), and notes from the diaries of his father, Albert Dunham Judd (1830-1908). In addition to the diaries there are five memo books and three miscellaneous documents. The Judds were a prominent Connecticut family involved in manufacturing and active in community affairs. Albert D. Judd moved from New Britain to New Haven in 1864, simultaneously selling his interest in the family business, M. Judd & Co. of New Britain, and becoming president of the Judd Manufacturing Company in New Haven. That business moved to Wallingford in 1878, becoming part of H. L. Judd & Co., and he followed it there with his family after a year's residence in Orange, New Jersey. The diaries number 36 volumes covering the years 1861 to 1944. They include discussions of politics, business dealings, real estate, and the social life and customs of the day. They were received from the Whitlock Farm Booksellers on February 2, 1973.
Families; Connecticut -- Social life and customs; Middle West; New Haven (Conn.); Diaries; Judd, Albert Dunham; Judd, Albert Lemuel, 1864-; Judd, Ethel Gardiner, 1869-; Judd, Katharine Wells
- Inventory
  - Albert Lemuel Judd
    - Notebook of Albert Lemuel Judd containing notes from the diaries of his father, Albert Dunham Judd from 1861-1907, and notes from the diaries of Albert Lemuel Judd, 1881-1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Notes from the diary of Albert Dunham Judd transcribed by Albert Lemuel Judd, 1881-1889, 15 pages (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Diaries
      - 1886 Jan 1-Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1888 Mar 9-1893 Jan 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1889 May 5-1890 Aug 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1893 Jan 1-Mar 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1898 Mar 2-1902 Jun 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1902 Jun 29-1903 Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1905 Mar 23-Dec 11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1905 Dec 11-1906 Jul 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1906 Jul 15-1907 Jun 22 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1907 Jun 22-1908 Mar 7 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1908 Mar 8-1909 Mar 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1909 Apr 18-1910 Feb 21 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1910 Mar 1-1911 Jan 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1911 Feb 12-1912 Mar 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1912 Mar 10-1913 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1913 Jun 8-1914 Sep 27 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1914 Oct 4-1915 Dec 26 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1917 Jan 7-1918 Mar 10 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1919 Dec 7-1921 Jul 17 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1921 Jul 17-1922 Jan 26 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1924 Feb 7-1925 Nov 27 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - 1925 Dec 12-1927 Sep 11 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - 1927 Sep 12-1929 Jun 16 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - 1929 Jun 23-1930 Aug 17 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - 1930 Aug 31-1932 Nov 13 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - 1932 Nov 20-1934 Sep 11 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - 1937 Jul 11-1940 Jun 8 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - 1940 Jun 30-1942 Aug 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - 1942 Aug 30-1944 Jul 23 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Memorandum books (3) and cash book, 1930 May 1-1944 August 2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Katherine Wells Judd
    - Diaries
      - 1878 Jan 1-1880 Aug 3 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - 1882 Jan 2-Feb 11 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - 1882 Apr 1-Nov 11 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - 1883 Jan 1-1884 Dec 6 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - 1887 Jan 8-Dec 31 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ethel Gardiner Judd
    - Diaries
      - 1886 Jan 1-31 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - 1886 Feb 1-Mar 8 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - 1886 Jan 25 (1 page) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Memo book, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Poem "To My Daughter Adelaide Louise [Gettine?] Gardiner on her birthday anniversary November 20th1902" (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "Results of Works for the year ending April 30th1873" (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "List of Stockholders in the Douglas Axe Mfg. Co. June 13, 1859" (Box 3, Folder 18)